He just basically only finds mega crits,
right? So it's like it's say for
Chapman, right? Like Chapman has 20
bucks a year and makes more than all
everyone else. This guy's average payout
is like, you know, 15 grand ridiculous.
Like
best part of when you can just, you
know, critical think
[Music]
Okay, look guys, you know I'm a little
bit picky about sponsors for this
podcast, right? And this next sponsor I
personally went and sought out myself.
So hang tight, listen for a second and
let me tell you about them. Okay, this
is the Adobe Bug Bounty program and they
are one of the best bug bounty programs
out there. A ton of hackers love their
program and really respect it. Um, and
they're a brand we all know and love,
right? who hasn't used an Adobe product
over the years. Um, they're a public
program, so you can hack on it with your
friends super easily. The bounties are
great. And guys, the scope is unmatched.
They've got wildcard domains. They've
got massive primary apps like Adobe
Photoshop and Lightroom. Uh, they've got
open source software like Magento, aka
Adobe Commerce. They've got executables
like Cold Fusion if you're looking to do
some of that like Shubsesque uh zeroday
research on architectural related stuff.
They've got mobile apps like Adobe
Reader and uh Photoshop mobile. It is a
freaking treasure trove of scope, you
guys. And like we always say in the pod,
you should hack on targets that have
live hacking events if you want to get
invited to live hacking events, right?
And Adobe has been in the Ambassador
World Cup for the past two years. They
are on the live hacking event scene. So,
it's definitely a good target to look at
from that front as well. Also, for
critical thinking listeners, they are
looking to get some new traffic on their
Android and iOS apps. So, they're
offering you guys an exclusive 50% bonus
on your first valid report uh on mo on
on mobile apps on inscope mobile apps.
So, just use the code CTBP619.
That's CTBP critical thinking bugbounty
podcast 619 in your report and you'll
get a 50% bonus. This they're going to
run this promotion through the end of
July and you can find the program on
hacker1.com/adobe.
All right, I'm going to go hack on them
a little bit. I hope you guys do too.
Tear them up for us. It is a great way
to support the pod. All right, let's go
back to the show. Sup hackers. We've got
a pretty sick This Week in Bug Bounty
segment this week. So, let's jump right
into it. First up is Yes Week Kaido by
Yes We Hack. That is a plugin that
integrates directly into Kaido that
shows you uh your scope and what kind of
programs you can attack um within the
Yes, We Hack ecosystem. So, for example,
I'm in here. I'm just going to search
for uh Louis Vuitton. And I can see
right here um all their scope. I can add
the scope. I can add the user agent. Um,
so this reduces friction for you
switching targets or getting details
about your target uh if you're working
within the Kaido ecosystem. So pretty
sick. I think we'll see a couple of
these plugins kind of come on the
ecosystem um where you'll be integrating
with bug bounty platforms directly
within your HP proxy. Pretty sick.
Pretty sick. Um, all right. Next up is
more stuff from Yes, We Hack. They've
been kind of pumping stuff out lately.
Um, the the next one I wanted to talk
about was their uh Recon Series 5, a
guide to Google dorking. Okay. And I
don't know if you guys use Google
Dorking as much as I do, but I Googled
dork a lot. So, this is a pretty sick um
guide to kind of get you back up to
speed on um what kind of uh operators
you can use um and how to do uh Google
Dorking to increase your recon. And one
of the things I love about Google
Dorking is Google knows what's important
about a target, right? They index it.
That's how people find things about
these companies. So, I think it's a
really good like generic way to um to
hack on a specific target. Next up is
the dojo uh with uh Yes, We Hack as
well. Um I don't know if you guys knew
this, but Yes, We Hack dojoos get you
private program invites on Yes, We Hack.
Um this one right here is Hex Color
Pallet, and I'll give you a little hint,
it's an XXE. So, go check that out if
you're looking to get some private
program invites and pop into the Yes, We
Hack uh ecosystem there. All right, next
up is from Hacker One. We've got an
article on smart contracts and common
vulnerabilities in real world cases. I
know a lot of hackers have been out
there killing it in web 3
vulnerabilities and making a ton. Um, so
if you're looking to sort of refresh
your knowledge on this, also shout out
to my boy Andrew Pratt that wrote this
article. Love it. Um, then you can kind
of refresh your knowledge on price
oracle manipulation, uh, logic errors,
re-entry attacks, flash loan attacks,
all sorts of things. Um, this is the
kind of stuff I I deep dived a while
back and then have sort of let that
knowledge fade. So, I think I'm going to
go refresh on this myself.
All right. Um, last but not least is Bug
Crowd. And actually, this is a pretty
exciting announcement, you guys. Um, Bug
Crowd has actually launched a Red Team
as a service offering. And obviously,
this is cool for organizations. So, if
your organization needs Red Team
services, definitely check this out. But
this is cool for us as the hackers too
because we can potentially get in on
this, especially if you're in the Bug
Crowd ecosystem already. Um, and I know
a lot of you guys participate in uh the
Bug Crowd or Hacker One um, you know,
pentest offering and this is Bug Crowd
sort of pushing that industry forward
and adding Red Team as a service in to
that uh that flow. Um, so definitely if
you're a little bit more on the red team
side, then definitely want to check this
out. They are recruiting for this from
the crowd. they've said, I think down in
like the FAQs here. Um, so definitely go
ahead and check that out if you're
interested in getting in on some
contract work to supplement that that
Bug Bunny income. All right, that's a
wrap for this week. Let's go back to the
show.
All right, dude. Let's let's just jump
right into the mouth of the beast this
time because there's been some [__]
going on in the book bounty community
while I was away on this on this
vacation. Yeah, I did have to bring down
the the uh smackdown with the with
everyone tagd.
Yeah, dude. Yeah. So, all right. You
know, we we we kind of discussed it off
air. We're we're starting this recording
a little bit late because we had to like
figure out exactly what we wanted to
say. And um without bringing too much
drama uh into the pod,
like I think it's I think we had one
major thing that we wanted to reassure
you guys of um about this whole drama
thing. That's right. Drama is gonna come
up from time to time. We really want to
give a shout out to three people. Okay.
to Kodingo to Ybert and to Ini. Okay,
these these are the guys That's right.
that are are real hackers that that
hack. I've seen and been impressed by
their hacks many times. They are working
for these platforms and they are
advocating for you guys, the hackers.
So, you know, whatever happens, they're
human. They they make mistakes, but know
that their heart is in the right place
for the bug bounty community. Right. Am
I am I conveying that right, Joseph? Is
that what we wanted to say? Yeah,
exactly. I mean, those guys not only
helped build Bug Bounty into the
industry that it is today, but they've
consistently fought for hackers and for
just the embment of humanity for years
to come. And like you just said, they
might not make the perfect call every
time. But I think that anyone who's out
there that is skeptical of their hearts
or what they're trying to promote or
build is in the wrong place and they
need to reevaluate their opinions. the
the these guys especially advocating for
hackers are not are not out to get you
in the and we did want to say there's
not lots of we're not excluding lots of
other people who are who are working at
bug bounty programs or platforms but
those guys for sure are often leading or
at least commenting on things that are
public or making decisions behind the
scenes and um yeah you can trust their
hearts. Yeah, absolutely. All right,
man. Well, I know that that's what we
wanted to say. Um so let's let's get to
the meat. Let's get to the meat and we
we won't address the the drama any
further. Um, okay. Well, first thing of
the meat actually is uh a new newsletter
that came out called Disclosed by Harley
from H1. Um, and this he does a pretty
freaking good I mean, have you seen it?
Have you seen the Dude, it's And we're
not sponsored. We're not sponsored by
Harley here. We are not sponsored. We
have no uh affiliation. We just love
Grassroots products. It's good, dude. I
mean, like Harley has a, you know, his
thumb on the pulse of the bug bounty
community. Um, and this is a thorough
ass newsletter. It is. He's putting a
lot of work into it. That was my first
thought. Yeah. And I don't understand
how he's launching like six things at
once, too. Like, he launched the We're
We're covering it later, but, you know,
he launched his his um vibe coding, man.
It's all vi Yeah, it's it's vibe coding,
but the domain is kind of crap, but what
what is it? Disclosed online. you know,
I think he maybe bought two domains,
like one for the disclosed newsletter
and then he used it to like put the
hacker profiles on. It's kind of
cohesive. Um, sorry if you think about
it. Yeah. Yeah. Um, but yeah, I think
that the disclosed newsletter is
definitely worth a sub. Um, especially
if you if you want to just have a good
list of I mean, what is this? This is a
there's a bunch of things on here.
There's learn, there's videos, there's
tweets, there's articles, um, writeups.
like he's got a bunch of different
sections inside this newsletter which I
really like. So even if you don't want
to hear about the tweets or you don't
really care about the tools, you can
just jump straight to writeups and
research, you know. That's right. And
and uh and get a really good update on,
you know, what's happening in that
specific section of the bug bounty
community this week. So yeah, in
general, I just love anything that's
bugy focused because I mean that's the
reason why you started the podcast
initially. It's like we like Bug Bounty
itself deserves an ecosystem of like
products and media and content.
And if you want to excel at anything,
you want to basically submerge yourself
in that. I think people do that in lots
of other industries and niches. And it
was hard for Bug Bounty for a while
because the only way you could get that
content was really like just following
people on social media or being in
private Slacks or Discords. And I think
uh in large part critical thinking, you
know, quote unquote solved that problem
in a big way. But this is just another
great way that you can immerse yourself
in Bug Bounty content. Yeah. Yeah, dude.
I mean, I I think it I think it it
should be clear from the fact that we
run a competitor newsletter to this and
yet we are still shouting it out on the
podcast that uh you should definitely
check it out because it is it is very
high quality. Um so also check on a
completely different note, subscribe to
the critical thinking newsletter at
ttv.show/blog.
Exactly. Um also also really well done
but a little bit more oriented towards
the pod, right? Like what we do on that
newsletter, just for those of you that
aren't familiar, is we take the news we
covered on the pod. We take the the
technical details of what we said on the
pod and we try to give you a way to
access that data in text just in case
you don't have the opportunity to listen
to the whole episode or maybe you need
you remember like a oneliner that we
said or like some some topic that you
need to go back and get a refresher on.
Well, you can find it, you know, in text
on the on the Yeah. or you need a
payload or you need it's basically like
it's it's basically like show notes
plus+ like it's like a much more
expanded version of show notes. Exactly.
Yeah. All right. I think you have more
than me so I'm going to jump to one of
mine. Do it. Um so XSS doctor
as we all know puts out great stuff. Um
let me uh hide my messages before I
share my screen because our editors
always have to edit that out. Uh I'll
share my screen. Yeah, dude. This is
really cool. I'm surprised this wasn't
on your list. Did you see this? I did
see it. Yeah, I I missed it and I even
had it bookmarked. Uh but I I did miss
it. Yeah. So, basically Excess Doctor
found a really cool CSP bypass where he
uploaded a valid PDF, but because the
magic bytes in PDFs are not at the
beginning of the file. It can it can
also be a completely valid JavaScript
file. So, it's a valid So, it's just a
polyglot file that's both a PDF and a
JavaScript file. And it's funny like
this is the entire file. Um, but it's
based on a really good blog um, from
Doyens, uh, which we've talked a lot
about on the podcast. So, um, you can go
check that out. You can go also check
out this tweet, but um, extremely cool
payload. And do you think this has been
done before and just like not shared?
Yeah, I I've seen it before and actually
I've I've talked to XS doctor about
this. You know, we we've kind of
compared notes on on this sort of like
polyglot uh, type of payloads before
because it's very relevant to uh, client
side path traversal, which we are both
very passionate about, right? is kind of
figuring out a way, okay, you know, is
there any way that I can upload, you
know, valid JSON in another file format
type, you know, that sort of thing. Um,
definitely a cool trick. Um, PDFs in
particular, I think, are pretty
malleable. Um, so definitely definitely
one to to check out. And actually, man,
we've got pretty relevant I've got two
relevant um pieces to this uh actually.
So, I'm I'm gonna Did you have any other
comments on that? I can tie it into
Definitely. you know, very cool to have
that PDF as like a valid um JavaScript
executable type there. Um, tying it into
a different thing, there's also write up
by Jorian uh Walter. I'm sorry, I can't
get I don't know the name, but uh on OBS
websocket RC. Is this a different Jorian
than the other Jorian? No, this is this
is Jorian. Okay. Yeah, this is Jorian.
That's that's around all the time. Yeah.
Um Yeah. And and this was a great write
up. Um, and like Jorian is is a
phenomenal hacker. So I'm in no way nay
saying this that uh you know that this
is not as impactful or you know that it
wasn't great work. Yeah, there was a
caveat within the first like two
paragraphs of like if you turn off
authentication then you can do this
exploit. I'm like okay that is a big if.
But the the um techniques that he used
to actually fully do the exploit um with
the websocket interactions and uh the
polyglot file of the the BMP here. Let
me go ahead and share my screen so you
guys can see what I'm talking about. Um
uh was was really cool. So I I did want
to tie that out because while we were
while we were talking about sort of
polyglot files, um this is an area where
he was able to craft a polyglot file.
Mhm. Um and so the TLDDR of this writeup
is that um in OBS you can turn on this
websocket based functionality and then
if you if you turn off the
authentication for it then uh any
website can just connect to your local
host for 455 and send commands into OBS
and um some of those commands are like
for example saving a a screenshot um and
and you can write to arbitrary files on
the the file system. So he's like okay
well how do I convert this into rce
right um using the very limited type of
well it's not very limited there's a lot
of supported images here but one of the
supported image types was BMP and BMP uh
has the ability for you to specify
essentially just arbitrary bytes within
that that file um as a representation of
the image data right so um I I'll I'll
I'll read this little um snippet from
the write up uh the bitmap file format
is very simple one especially its pixel
array variant which OBS uses when you
save an image as BMP as it uses no
compression as you can see above it
stores BGR values which I'm more
familiar with RGB but I think it's like
flipped the endiness of it is flipped um
values uh by one as separate bytes if
the first pixel is colored as you know
hex 72 uh 644A and the second one is uh
6E 6169 its BGR values will turn into
the byte string just repeating those
back or the ASI equivalent of it is the
word Jorian which is his name right so
essentially what you can do is you can
use BMPPS to smuggle arbitrary like uh
bytes into this this this file without
having to deal with like image
compression and some of the other
nuances that you'll run into with other
uh image types so it makes it very um
easy to use BMP as a a polyglot file um
that you can achieve different types of
exploits So what he ended up actually
doing here was using it to uh craft and
this is another really cool tip dude
ahta application right which is an
executable format in Windows uh that
will allow you to just run arbitrary uh
VBScript um and the other cool thing
about that HDA file is that it is fuzzy
so you know it's just HTML in there
right um and then you have access to
writing DBScript inside of a script tag
Um, so and HTML is very like other bytes
compatible, right? It's just going to be
perceived as like just text, right,
inside of the inside of the um file. So
you can put all the the BMP related
stuff in there and then just, you know,
use that arbitrary amount the ability to
just write arbitrary bytes that we
talked about before to build out a
script that will actually run in a
Windows environment um and and popcal.
So he was able to do that and built the
whole pock out. Um, so I think that is
really really phenomenal work. I'm not
sure how intently you you read it. I
because I haven't read it yet, but um
did it like what made it pop when you
restarted OBS? Like why did it how did
it execute the bit maps hdta? So uh
that's that's a trick. He actually wrote
it to the the startup folder in in
Windows. So he had like because because
you have arbitrary right. Yeah. Yeah.
Yeah. Yeah. Cool. He could write the
files anywhere. So he wrote it to the
startup inside of um inside of Windows
and then it would automatically run the
HDA file and pop perfect. That's
awesome. Um the the interesting thing is
obviously in order to do that you need a
gadget that leaks the user's username,
right? Um but actually one of the
functionalities that OBS exposed via
that websocket was uh something that
leaked the path and and you could use it
to grab the the the username. Nice. So
uh very good work by Jorian as always.
Two takeaways there is uh BMP files are
super helpful for sort of dirty file
rights right and then hta you know
combined with that is um compatible with
dirty files and will still allow you to
get execution on on a Windows system.
Yep.
Sweet. Uh the one thing I was going to
mention um next was a write up by
Kazushi. I didn't even know this but his
name is apparently Andrew. Um, I think I
mentioned it before whenever we uh
whenever we were talking about one of
his blog post. It was the precursor to
this one or like the the one that came
before this. And I mentioned it because
he's big into judo. Like he's like a
second degree black belt in judo which
is super cool. And a hacker. So yeah,
being into martial arts plus hacking is
very cool. Um anyways, so he wrote a
blog called Time in a Bottle or
Knapsack. and he's talking about um it's
kind of a continuation on the fact if
you remember the last one talked about
how he was trying to come up with some
sort of formula by which you could
determine like the odds of finding a
vulnerability and it involved as a big
part of that formula like the amount of
times you tried and I think I mentioned
or if I didn't you know one big thought
of this is like this is why like fuzzing
or scanning or vulnerability you know
scanning or um this sort of like try a
lot of things often like or like using
active scanner in in burp or using
whatever other types scanners is like so
valuable is because you're getting a lot
of shots, even if they're not on goal.
It's just by taking a lot of shots, you
are often going to increase your odds of
success. Um, so he talks a little bit
more about that, but the part about this
u, and you all can go and read the blog,
you should. It'll be in the show notes.
But the one thing in here that I thought
was really neat was he was talking
about, you know, potentially going
full-time as a bug hunter and what that
would mean and how it would require him
to, you know, make a decent amount of
money. And so in here he specifically
says, you know, like let's say an
average um you know, a secure or yeah,
security consultant makes something like
$150,000 a year or whatever. Then you
know, he says random sources show the
average payouts between $500 or $1,000
per issue. Um and I can confirm that,
you know, what's really cool, hacker one
shows you what your average payout is.
And so me and you and other hackers have
talked about this before. or it it is
often around, you know, that I think
people who are more on the critical or
high end of things often have it more
between a,000 and 1,500 or whatever. But
yeah, so then he uses that math to say,
okay, if I make $750 per vulnerability,
how many vulnerabilities do I need to
make $150,000 a year or whatever, and it
comes out between 250 and 300
vulnerabilities. But then if you assume
that you know 20% of your
vulnerabilities are going to be dupes
orformational or false positives then
now you can multiply that again by you
know increase another 20% to figure out
exactly how many bugs you would need per
year on average to make a make a good
salary. This is stressful for me dude
I'm not going to lie like looking at
these numbers. Yeah I know it's it's
basically one a day is what it comes out
to. It's it's um which you know
obviously there are lots of hackers like
um Inspector if any of you Inspector
Ambitious I think is his name he got MVH
at the Google event that I went to in
Malaga last year he just basically only
finds mega crits right so it's like and
say for Chapman right like Chapman has
20 bucks a year and makes more than all
everyone else average payout is like you
know 15 grand or something ridiculous
like that exactly so there's lots of
different outliers and there are some
people with great automation that find
you thousand bugs a year. But anyways,
yeah, this is this is really cool. But
basically, for a Western world salary,
if you want to if you're in the US and
you want to be a full-time bug hunter,
you need to average like one bug a day.
And I will say, don't overly stress
about it if you're a listener because
that never works out for me. It's
basically like I'll get an invite to a
new program or a hacker one challenge or
I'll get into a new area of scope and
I'll find six bugs in a day or something
and then, you know, then you won't find
any for a while. But I just thought that
was really cool the way he broke that
down. Yeah. So, a couple comments on
this one is um I think you should plug
in your own numbers as a hacker into
this because um I know that my average
payout is substantially higher than
those numbers and and I and I think that
it depends on what kind of hacker you
are and uh the frequency, right? Because
I I know that there are some hackers out
there, even manual hackers, that just
turn out mediums all freaking day,
right? You know, and and they make great
money, phenomenal money. And and I don't
get me wrong, I am not below reporting,
you know, a low or medium or anything
that that the company finds value. Um,
but I think look at your own stats when
when factoring all this in because um I
think you can make substantially more
than what he's calculating here um by
submitting substantially less
vulnerabilities, correct? Um depending
on, you know, what kind of programs
you're targeting as well um and the
average payouts for those. Um, the
second thought here was that I love
these I love these formulas for bug
bounty. And I've actually tried I'm not
sure I can get it up while I'm talking
here. I'll try to pull it up. But um the
there I have a formula that I kind of
put into my talk on um you know hacking
efficiently and I I believe I no this
was at village last year. So I don't
think that um I I've talked about it you
know publicly before. I know that I do
have a recording in the in the critical
thinking um discord, but I love these
formulas of like, okay, there's like
here we calculate our attack vector
value. You know, we've got the
probability of success, you know, the
impact of success, the the friction to
actually test it. You know, you're
pulling all these variables together.
And I I do have mine out there. Maybe
I'll send it out in a tweet or
something. But all of that really came
from a talk for me from way back by
Matias Carlson actually where he did a
talk at like some obscure um uh like
conference. I I forget what it was. Um
but he gave a talk on how to optimize
your bug bounty. Yeah. And I I think I
asked him about it last time he came on
the pod and we're going to have him on
the pod again soon. So so I'll I'll ask
him about it again. But I think not
enough there hasn't been enough research
done by researchers into the metagaming
of bug bounty like this, right?
How can we optimize our efficiency as as
hackers and and produce the ma most
output? Yeah, I think that that was I
think that when you look at people like
you or like Douglas or other top
hackers, I think that they
subconsciously have found that product
market fit. Product market fit is a
weird word, but I feel like they found
that like personal time spent fit really
well because like you're incentivized to
optimize for it based on the fact that
you get paid in Bug Bounty. So, I I do
think you're right that not enough
people kind of think about it or
research it or focus on it, but I do
think one, it's a little bit
personalized. And then two, I do think
people kind of find it for themselves
because they're trying to optimize for
it because they want to make the most
money, but they often could make even
more changes. Um, I just looked mine up.
My my average is actually 1,200, so it
is a bit higher as well. Um, so, um,
yeah, I agree. I think that it's really
neat. I think that the formulas do kind
of help people. And I think that um one
big factor that I think you do well and
that other kind of top hackers do well
is kind of being a little bit ruthless
in time spent and like how you spend
your time. Um it's like you almost can't
be ruthless enough in how you're
spending your time. But that doesn't
mean like always switching. It might
mean just like blocking off all
communication path so that you can solo
focus and go deep, right? But then
sometimes it does mean switching. Um and
just kind of I think that um what you
kept doing during that Google event that
I think about a lot is that you were
like um at least maybe twice a day but
at least once a day basically saying
like hey what are the most promising
leads and this is like kind of similar.
Alexi actually talked about this on his
mo on one of his most recent YouTube
videos talking about business priorities
and he was saying like as a CEO you
often have this laundry list of ideas
you want to implement in the business
but when you implement one there's like
a there's like a loss. you like take a
quick performance loss. And so if and so
you basically need to rank those based
on the probability of success and how
much how um likelihood it not just
probability but then what kind of impact
it will have if it does work. And so I
think as a as a hacker you can do that
exact same thing. It's like if you have
six leads and this is what I was saying
that you did well at that Google event.
Basically we would have like six leads
or six ideas to pursue. you would
prioritize those based on your your
rough mental math on like odds of
success of those and then how critical
the payout is or how critical the impact
is based on that. And I think doing that
mental math you probably do that often
when you're actually looking through a
through a program and in live hacking
events you probably do the same thing.
And so maybe that's a really solid tip
for the listeners is like if you have a
lot of things to look at or a lot of
ideas or a lot of leads or a lot of
errors you should you should actually
take a second to step back. Don't just
go down that rabbit hole that you're all
prone to go down and but list them out
and think which of these is the highest
likelihood of success and which of these
will pay the best if it does exceed.
Yeah. Yeah. And I think a lot of that is
informed by intuition as well because we
can't quantify these things. Right.
Right. Um or or you know we can it is
probably quantifiable but you know we I
haven't seen an effective way to do that
yet. So you know my my way that I
quantify these is by intuition and for
that you have to be a pretty experienced
hacker. So this isn't really oriented
towards beginners. This is oriented
towards intermediate advanced people
that are looking to optimize their
output. Yeah. Um all right, dude. We we
have to move along, but uh the the talk
that I mentioned before is called how to
differentiate yourself as a bug hunter
by Matias Carlson at OAS Stockholm. So
we'll drop that in the description. Um
definitely a recommended watch. Uh very
impactful uh talk in in my opinion. Mhm.
Um all right, we are we are not doing
No, listen. You're being negative. Shake
off the shack. Shake off the negative,
Nancy. We're doing great. The the
audience is loving it. We're doing
great. All right. All right. Let's do
it, dude. All right. Next up, uh on the
list, I had hacked in versus disclosed
online. This is the thing we we
mentioned before, you know, with Harley
spinning up a essentially bug bounty um
profile aggregator. And this is actually
something that critical thinking has
been thinking about doing for a long
time and we just haven't been able to
allocate resources to it. Um, but I'm
kind of relieved that some of these
other people are taking it on. Um, and
so obviously there's two of these out
here that kind of spun up at the exact
same time. Uh, hackedin.net and
disclosedonline.com.
Um, I love Harley. I love both of these
these products. My thought is that
hackedin.net is is currently in the
lead. Um, and I think this bring in the
hot tape. I like it. Yeah, I you know, I
got I got to do it. Um, you know,
there's there's some self-signup
features. Uh they're working on actually
like verifying your your profile with um
emails. You know, they send an email to
like your reherator at weehacker1.com
email or whatever. This is very visual.
So I'm going to show the two. Yeah.
Yeah. Show them. This is what this is
what disclosed online looks like for my
profile. So it's got like my ex stats,
hacker one stats, bug crowd stats,
GitHub with top repos, and then it kind
of pulls out companies you help secure
and then testimonials from hacker one as
well. And then the other one. Oh, it's
nice. It pulled your testimonials.
That's cool. Yeah. And then hacked in.
Yeah. Show them hacked in. And and and
so, you know, I think that the reason
this is necessary for the industry is
that you kind of want to at a glance
understand
if this person that's talking actually
hacks, right? And I've been, you know, I
I I don't really give a lily about this
quite as much anymore because I think
I've I've sort of established myself
already as a hacker. But it does make me
a little sad to look at my Hacker One
profile and and show like, you know,
three bugs submitted in the past like
couple months right now because I've
been focusing on Google exclusive. Well,
not just that. I just I hate that it
defaults to last 90 days. Like I I
really wish it defaulted to all time on
Hacker One just and maybe that's because
I'm the same way, right? I feel like,
you know, historically, like I've got
12,000 rep on Hacker One, but then you
pull up hacker1.com/reso and it's like,
like you said, like 10 bucks or 500 rep
or whatever. Yeah. So, this is what
hacked in looks like once you've got
everything set up. Um, one thing that
the skills don't have enough options
like there's no AI related skills that
you can add. I do I do like the fact
that uh it lets you choose these two
things. They could also pull these from
LinkedIn or or X. Um, kind of nice. But
it is neat to see, you know, how like I
I I think I like this a little bit
better where it shows like the rep and
vulnerabilities across this. Even though
they don't line up the same, it's cool
to see both of those. And I thought this
was like a really nice touch that it it
shows the um it shows the stars on your
most popular repo. Yeah. Yeah. I I like
that as well. And and so there's a
couple things I just kind of wanted to
brainstorm with you live on on this sort
of thing. Couple features that I think
should be implemented. Um, I think that
they should imple I mean platform
verification is necessary. So you you
shouldn't let people link any hackers
profile to their account. Um, so they're
they're working on that. I know. Um, I
would also like to see integration with
top programs that are outside of the
platforms like Google and Meta to name
at least two. Um, and then I would like
to see some formula to aggregate and
crossorrelate the reputation and the
bugs submitted and pull it into an
overall hacker score. Interesting.
Right. So that at a glance, at one
glance I can say, okay, Joseph's talking
some some [__] you know, like what what
has he popped lately, you know, sort of
situation, right? Um, and I think that's
the biggest value ad. So what do you
think is the real utility of this? This
still feels like a gimmick to me. Like
no, no offense to either of them, but
it's like besides I it is kind of nice
like you said to have a single place to
go to to say like should I respect this
person's like opinion or is this person
legit from like a technical perspective
and it is hard to know sometimes like
you said because there are people like
um Yousef that are like all meta, right?
He's submitted everything is meta and so
if some if someone didn't respect him
it'd be like kind of weird or
interesting cuz he's so technically
skilled. And there's some sleepers out
there, man, in the community that are
like killers or whatever, but but they
don't tweet and they don't write blogs.
And if they don't tweet and they don't
write blogs, they don't have a hacker
one profile, you know, or whatever, then
you don't know if they're popping bugs,
you know, and and and I think at the end
of the day, um, one of the things we
love about the bug bounty community is
it's PC or GTFO, right? So, if you are
not actually popping bugs, then we know,
you know, and and like and and you know,
you're
It's just a very PSC or GTFO community
and I really value that. Right. Yeah. Um
and that's why it's important to me as
somebody who runs this podcast to be
actively hacking. Um and and and you
know trying to to actually make sure
that you guys know that I'm not just
coming here and talking the talk. I am
popping on the daily. Yeah. You're on
the battlefield with them. Yeah. Yeah.
Exactly. So anyway, I think this is very
necessary. Um the the hacker score thing
I think would be huge. The other thing
that I just want to say is I would like
to be able to go to a hacker one
profile, a bug crowd profile, you know,
whatever, and change one letter in the
domain and end up on this site. Oh gosh.
Right. You know what I'm saying? Like,
so it needs to be like hacker ones, you
know, or like uh hug crowds. I couldn't
I couldn't believe you said that the
domain was bad. Hacked in I thought was
really clever and I wish I thought of
it. Hacked in is good. Hacked in is
good. You just want to be com instead
of.net. No. No, no, no. Hacked in is
great. Uh, I was saying you said that
their domain suck. You said their
domain. Oh, did I say domain? Yeah, you
said both need a better do. No, I'm
going to quote you in this. Pull up the
doc. It says both need a better domain.
Run it back right now. It says I can
screenshot it if you want me to. It says
both need a better domain. Oh [__] I
did. It's got to be because of thenet or
something. You had to be thinking
something. You're right. I did put that
in the in the Okay, don't run it back,
Richard. Richard, do not run it back.
You're right. I did say that and I I see
what you're saying like LinkedIn hacked
in. I get I think that's super clever.
Yeah. The dot I I I hacked in I think is
a good domain. Would love it to not
be.net but it is what it is. Disclosed
online doesn't say to me this is where I
go to find out about other hackers.
Right. Right. I think Hackin does. It's
like hey this is the social media
profile of that. Yeah. And actually, I'm
a little bit ashamed to say I think the
reason why I wrote this, you know, a
couple days ago was I didn't get it. I
didn't get Oh, maybe you didn't get it.
Yeah. Okay. Well, I mean, but if you
didn't get it, then will other people
get it? It's kind of something to think
about. It is, you know, and maybe it's
because it's a net thing. I don't know.
But either way, I'm glad to see these
popping up and I would like to, you
know, I think once the product is really
refined, um, very valuable and, uh,
yeah, if I if I don't, I would I will
definitely be supporting financially
whoever comes out on on top of this
whole thing between the two of them. Um,
you know, via donations or whatever
because I think this product needs to
continue to exist. So, yeah. And I I do
think it would be amazing if um there
was some way to make sure everyone uses
it. Like that's the frustrating part to
me is like if this if one of them gets
really good, I'm sure they will, but
then 20% of people use it, it's still
useless. Like it really has to be
something that gets adoption. Maybe
maybe if there isn't somebody who's
claimed profiles just like in Facebook,
that would be cool. If there isn't
someone who's claimed a specific
profile, then you just crossorrelate all
of the like assume they have the same
username, right? you know, and then say,
"Okay, everyone with the username
Renerator, even though he hasn't been on
here, looks like this." That's I said
shadow profile. I don't know if you know
what I mean. On Facebook, if you don't
have a Facebook account, it still takes
every face from every photo ever found
online. And there's a shadow profile for
you that when you sign up, you can be
like, "Oh, and here's all the photos I'm
tagged in." It's already associated with
a single face, like a holy. So, that's
what this would be, right? It' be like a
a shadow hack hacked in account. So,
gez, that's crazy, man. All right. What
you got? Cool. Yeah. So, this is like
two kind of AI security. Well, I've got
like three AI security things, but um
one, um what else is new, Joseph? I
know. Listen, I don't know if you all
know this, but I get lots of DMs that
are like, "Thank you so much for pushing
me into doing AI stuff," or, "Thank you
so much for teaching me about I also get
I'm sure that there's other actually I
don't get that much of it, but I'm sure
because people are probably kind, but
I'm sure there are some people who are
annoyed by it, but I will say there are
a lot of people who are very thankful of
it." So, yeah. Yeah. And I to be honest,
man, you know, one of the big
differentiating factors obviously, yeah,
I'm very grateful to have you on the
show, but one of the big differentiating
factors on inviting you on to the show
is I firmly believe that if we are not
utilizing AI correctly as bug bounty
hunters in the next 5 years, then you're
done. You're cooked, you know. And so I
think uh you know as far as the podcast
goes, we I'm very pleased to have a AI
specialist hacker on here as well to
talk about these things because uh
whether the community likes it or not,
I'm going to give them what they need,
which is uh an AI specialist in in Bug
Bounty. I love that. That's so much of
your heart just in outside of Bug
Bounty, too. You very much like I love
you and I'm going to make sure you're
doing uh well in life. I'm gonna make
sure I take good care of you. So all
right, sweet, man. That that that warms
the heart. I'm going to share my screen
on this one. Yes. What what you got?
Yeah. So, I have been thinking a lot
about AI stuff as I always do. I just
recently um am doing a short-term AI
safety engagement for OpenAI which I was
just excited to share because it's
pretty cool. Um they do need to up their
payouts and I sent them a long diet
tribe about why. But anyways, um so this
is a really cool AI write up. It's very
similar honestly to the stuff that we
found in Google Bard over a year ago.
Um, which is uh a little frustrating
because in this writeup they literally
say the first one ever. Um, anyways, I'm
going to click this link, share this tab
instead. Basically, they call Echolak.
It doesn't deserve a special name, guys.
Sorry, AIM Security. But what it is is
it's a markdown uh image Xville, which
for listeners who maybe are not or have
their head in the sand. Basically in AI
applications, if it will render a
markdown image, you can convince the
model to respond with a markdown image
link that then has a path or a query
parameter or a subdomain that includes
sensitive details about the conversation
or the user's history or their memory or
some other data. And then when it when
their browser makes a fetch request for
that um for that specific image, it
actually leaks it to your server in your
server logs, right? Right. And so that's
basically what they did here on um
Microsoft Copilot. For some reason, they
claim it's the first zero click attack
or something. Let me select. All right.
All right. Reszo, let it go, man.
Anyways, I know we did it first. We're
cool. All right, let's go. Uh well,
actually, so anyways, doesn't matter. Um
it wasn't it wasn't just us. Like lots
of other people found it, too. But
anyways, so what it does is um there's
some really cool stuff in here. One, it
was it was email based. So, you would
send an email to somebody who who uses
GitHub or sorry, Microsoft Copilot. And
um the thing that I tweeted about that I
thought was really cool was the fact
that this typical method of markdown
links didn't work. They used what's
called a referencebased markdown link.
So, let me zoom. Dude, I see that. Okay.
I saw you tweet this. This was super
cool. Yeah. Yeah. So, this is a
reference um style markdown link. And
you know what's even cooler? I don't
know if you saw this yet. If you didn't,
you're going to be so happy that this
happened. Jun Kokatu
shared this technique last November,
eight months ago, and no one really paid
attention to it. So, oh my gosh. I'm
going to share this tab instead.
Piloting Edge Co-Pilot is what I dropped
my phone. Yeah, he called it piloting
edge copilot right here. Um I'm going to
click on it and share this tab. So
basically he um said that when he was
hacking and doing a very similar attack
to echo leak or whatever they called it
basically they blocked this style the
typical style of markdown links but this
reference style was allowed and even
just the URL itself which is how a lot
of LM work right when they respond with
URLs it just automatically turns into
clickable which this is not as ref as uh
usable to what I'm talking about like
the embedded image markdown because this
will never get turned into an image but
this style can still be used as an
image. You just use an exclamation
point. So, I'll go really Oh, I didn't
know that. That's super cool. Yeah,
exactly. So, I'll go back to the main uh
AIM security post and show you
um share this tab instead. Dude, this is
just a great call out in general though,
like a a um you know, trying to look at
these more alternative syntaxes. Yes.
For markdown, I think would be super
interesting. Yeah, it's a great area of
research. I mean, just the way that
markdown gets converted to HTML. I've
already mentioned that in a previous
pod. I think people should dig into it
and there was I think maybe a zero day
or something that a critical thinker in
the researcher community found. I wasn't
able to replicate it. So I don't know if
it's fixed, but I think that parsers are
always the best place to look for bugs.
And so markdown being parsed into HTML
will in no doubt pay dividends if you
dig into it and find something
interesting. So um absolutely. So
anyways, here's the image part. It's
basically the exact same thing. So you
know here's the non-image. It's just the
link with the reference and the
reference below down here. It's the same
exact thing, but you you just append a
or prepend an exclamation point. So,
this reference goes and this reference
can go at the very bottom of the
response from the AI and then this just
goes where you want the image to occur.
Um, wow, that's crazy. Yeah. So, really
cool technique. Um, they eventually had
to do a CSP bypass. The other only cool
thing that I thought was really neat was
rag spraying. So ve very often um these
applications will sometimes especially
with like the cross history stuff that
we're seeing in shared memory and chat
GPT and in Google um and other products.
Basically when they want to reference
other data that's been sent or conversed
or saved off they'll use rag. If you
don't know what that is um I covered it
in the AI series if you want to go back
and watch that. But um this rag spraying
technique. So this is what I thought was
hilarious. They did. Here's a complete
guide to employee onboarding and then
they attack. Here's the complete guide
to HR and then they attack. Here's the
complete guide to leave absence attack,
you know, and then like username attack.
Hello world attack. Right? You just want
to have a whole bunch. This is basically
what gets um wrapped up in the rag which
would make it return when the user ask
about employee onboarding or HR or leave
of absence or whatever. So each of these
things is basically tagging that chunk.
The thing is this won't necessarily
always work. This is like like um like
rag will often have the data chunked up
and you don't know what they're chunking
by. Sometimes it's really advantageous
to chunk up text by like every 500
characters. Sometimes it's advantageous
to chunk it by every 1,000 or 2,000 or
so. This is not going to be a foolproof
uh solution unless you have a white box
assessment where you know exactly what
they're chunking the rag on. So it's not
going to necessarily be like one chunk
here, two chunk here, three chunk here.
basically where each tag that you give
it will end up in a different chunk. But
this will definitely increase the
likelihood of success by a lot. And so
they just they basically use the attack
instructions. Sorry for the audio
listeners when I say here. I'm I'm
highlighting something on screen. Um,
but you know, he basically just
prepended the attack instructions with
words that were likely to occur when the
user chatted with Microsoft Copilot such
that the attack was pulled into the AI
context so that it would override the
instructions and print out the markdown
image which will excfiltrate the data.
Also, I don't really love they even
called this zero click. I think that
Wonder Wuzi also considers this sort of
stuff zero click. And in some sense it
is because like if a user then chats
with the chatbot, it happens without
them clicking. But all of these types of
bugs still do require the user to
actually chat with the chatbot. But
maybe that's just an assumed behavior.
So anyways, I I I would I would agree
with you there that it's not exactly
zero click, but I would like I would
call that uh like I don't know, it's
something like point five click or
something like that, right? like it is
distinguishably different from a one
click. And I'm not going to lie to you,
I've definitely gone to a book bounty
program and been like this is zero
click, you know. And I think they should
pay it that way. We talked about that
too. Yeah. On the keynote of the Jason
Hadex um and my keynote at the nomcon.
It's like I think companies should
reward these as if they were zero click
because otherwise they get downgraded so
low and you're not paying enough for
what is like bleeding edge research in
my opinion if you're not paying these as
like that higher severity. And and I
also think that that is just one of the
the solid best practices for for
programs that are trying to be on the
forefront of bugani is like you know if
if you are able to trigger an exploit
with normal functionality of the
application right like if you the user
logs in well you know if they didn't log
in then no they're not using your app
you know so it doesn't really matter um
then then pay that as a zero click like
I've talked about it before but like I
had a bug where I had a CSS injection on
the dashboard homepage of a specific
site um that it was zero click. I could
just pl plop a CSS injection onto
somebody's dashboard and I just like
used it to hit a logout
URL and it would just you know they
would come to their they log in and then
instantly get logged out and so it was
like an application level DOSs. Um and I
think that's I mean that's as close to
zero click as you get you know um so
very interesting. I I I did want to say
rag spraying, you know, I do love when
different techniques from other parts of
the of the hacking world get
crossorrelated. Um, and I think this is
a great example of like, you know, just
across applying principles and and I
think that definitely this makes so much
sense with how rag works in general and
and and specifically useful for these
like.5 click right uh exploitation
scenarios. So very cool. Thanks for that
shout out, dude. I I did miss the meat
of this. Um, this is good. This is a
good one. I'm glad you liked it. And
it's cool that you got a little June
reference there, too. Yeah. Yeah. June
June does June does great stuff. What
did What did he say in this comment? Cuz
I I clicked. No, no one sees my stuff or
no one respond. He says, "No one pays
attention to my talk."
We love you, June. Sorry we missed it,
bro. Yeah. But yeah, guys, let's just go
give June a shout out. I I'm a little
bit salty at him cuz he got the Slunzer
image thing fixed immediately, which is
not great, but also partially my fault.
But definitely check out um Junior
Kokatu on on X. Um his handle is uh
shhjk.
Um and he puts out great stuff all the
time. Yep. Um all right, back to you.
Next up, yeah, next up is um from the
asset note team and shubs. Uh, a new
tool came out called Newtowner. And I
think that this is a really interesting
concept and I'm relieved that somebody
Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa. You're gonna
mention Shubs without mentioning that he
got MVH first. When I saw this link on
Shubs, I was like, "Oh, he's just going
to mention the Shubs. He's going to
congratulate Shubs." And instead, he
jumped straight to something else.
Congratulations, Shubs with the new MVH.
I tweeted about it at Yeah, you did. You
did. You did. Shubs, congrats, dude.
Also, dang it. He's getting to the point
where he's gonna pass you. like he's
it's going to be me and him and Fronn
with with the whole like winning closest
to top NBA's number of MBHS. I think
Matias is also up there actually. Um but
yeah, dude, shout out shout out to our
boy Shubs. Always always deserves it,
man. He always does. Um and on his own
soil, if if anybody doesn't know, the
life hacking event was in Australia,
which is where Shubs is from and lives.
And so yeah. And that that feels good,
dude. Next time they do it, they they
did one live hacking event in DC and
that was my first live hacking event
ever and I was like if they ever do one
in DC again, I'm going to like freaking
destroy that. But it did feel good to
win the the Tokyo LH for for um for
Google because it's not necessarily my
home soil, but you know kind of is maybe
like you live there for a while. I mean
if if you lived in a place it became a
it becomes a part of you. Yeah. All
right. Tell me about New Towner. Yeah.
So, New Towner is a new tool released by
the Asset Note team. Um, and essentially
it's like exploiting a nuance that we
see in a lot of cloud environments. Um,
which is that a lot of times, uh, as a
security mechanism, various assets will
will allow list a specific region or
data center or block of IP addresses. Um
and you can get access to those IP
addresses and proxy your traffic
through. Uh so New Towner uh exploits
that scenario and which was
traditionally a very hard scenario to
exploit. Um and they have support for
GitHub actions, GitHub, uh GitLab CI, uh
Bitbucket Pipelines, AWS API gateway, um
EC2, and Azure. Um all I'm sorry, Azure
is not yet supported, it says on the
status. Um, but essentially what this
allows you to do is uh check for
differences in URLs, HTTP or HTTPS uh
across when your traffic is coming from
these potentially allow listed IPs
versus from your normal like VPS or
whatever. Um, this blew my mind. It
makes so much sense. I mean, anyone who
has done large scale recon and just
finds thousands of domains that just
like error or don't respond or don't do
anything well. Whenever I saw this tweet
that says mutual TLS, not when you're
coming from ABS, 404 not found, not when
you're coming from ABS, it's like, oh
man. Yes. So, this is really cool. This
is genius. Yeah. It's a really great way
to get access to new scope or like green
green field unhacked things from a lot
of like these really large wild card
programs. I think this would unlock a
ton of like lowhanging fruit because
these things that are whitisted are
probably old and probably not looked at.
Yeah, absolutely. Yeah. I mean,
essentially, I imagine if you find a
differential between these two, then
it's almost always going to end up in a
bug. Um, so for any of you uh big recon
people, this could be a really good
thing to integrate because one of the
things that the recon folks sort of
struggle with um is the volume of all
the assets. And especially if you're
looking to do manual hacking, how do I
select one of these assets out of these,
you know, 5 million assets I've got to
spend my time on manually hacking? uh
you know and there have been all sorts
of attempts to do this with like let me
pull the JavaScript files and screenshot
or whatever single page application the
screenshot you know all that sort of
thing and I think this is another
indicator of like okay well if it's
responding differently when the IP
address is coming from AWS versus if
it's coming from my VPS then that's
another indicator that says maybe this
target Dude I bet this has already found
like caused so many vulnerabilities to
be found I'm sure it has I didn't I
didn't know what this was until
literally just now this is insane and
and the thing is man you know like you
can't implement everything, you know,
but I I I would say that I think this is
one of the things that really if you're
looking to differentiate yourself, not a
lot of people I've heard of are doing
this. I know that the Acido team has
been doing this for a while. I know that
um I I won't shout them out in
particular, but there there's one other
researcher that I know made a ton of
money off of this. Um but as a note once
again has your back leading the industry
releasing a tool for this. So, get it
implemented ASAP and be one of the first
ones to actually profit from it. I think
the reason why I love this so much, one,
I've done a lot of big recon and big
scanning, but I think two is
um I and I think you in particular and
other people are finding a lot more
value and a lot um higher ROI from
spending time on these big well-paying
programs. And this just screams to me
like use it on Google, use it on Yahoo,
use it on T-Mobile, you know, like use
it on Amazon. like the like some a
product like this is going to turn out
turn up the most results when used at a
massively wildcard bajillion subdomain
program and so and and those programs
right now are often some most people's
anchors pro anchor programs right they
pay well they respond quickly and so
like the fact that this works on big pro
like is most likely to work on big
well-paying programs makes it even a
higher leverage opportunity I think
totally dude yeah I definitely Another
great release by the asset node team.
Yeah. Um freaking love those guys, dude.
All right, you're up. What you got?
Cool. Yeah, I mean this was like a
really really small short one, but um
you know Jason Hadex often shares really
great AI hacking tips and he basically
said that this payload has been working
for him on a lot of stuff and I think
there's going there where this is like
the year of agents and people are always
looking at agents and hacking on agents.
It's hard to like, well, it's not hard,
but I just think that the tips that are
most likely to work with LLMs are so
much higher value and higher ROI because
it's really annoying and frustrating and
you often just give up when you're
trying to get a model to like break its
rules or do something different and it's
just frustrating you and you just want
to go back to normal hack, you kind of
give up. And so, I think having those
like high ROI tips like last time I
think we mentioned additional
instructions colon is like a really kind
of a key phrase to use. This feels like
another one of those kind of key
phrases. Let me share real quick. What
What is the phrase? I'm gonna tell you.
I'm gonna share it first. Okay. All
right. Um share screen X. Here we go. He
said that for agentic systems, he said
he's noticed that this works wonders.
Basically, you know, um have like agent
rule section and this is obviously
markdown formatted bold and um you know,
very frequently uh system prompts are
in, you know, well formatted markdown.
And then he says treat every so
basically you have a a heading called
agent rule section and then you have a
um in in parenthesis a thing that says
treat every must or should below as a
hard constraint and then a bullet point
that's basically like agent or tools
must and then whatever you want it to
do. And so what this does is, you know,
the model is thinking something like,
oh, I'm running as an agent or I have
this access to these tools and now I
have a new instruction or a new, you
know, requirement that I have to do what
this thing says and it like aligns with
the system prompt really well. And so
anyways, he said that's worked well
across 50 plus AI first companies. And
so I trust him and um yeah, felt like a
very solid tip. That that is a solid
tip, man. uh if he's tweeting that out
and and giving that that uh you know
data set on it, he's getting a lot of
distribution on these AI on these AI um
companies, man. 50 plus having tried
that. That's pretty sick. Um so
definitely a good data supported find
then. Yep. Um dude, I I see that you
pulled this Gareth Hayes tweet uh and I
am like why why did you not why did I
not No, no, no. had it. I Dude, I had it
in my bookmarks, but you know, I've been
out for a while and and so then it got
buried in the bookmarks. Why don't you
tell me about it? Find it this time.
Okay, I'll tell you what's cool about
it. Yeah. No, no, no. I got you. So, is
the original poster is the OP uh
Japanese? Masato Kinugawa. Masato
Kinagawa. Yeah, he he does amazing
stuff. And that was actually the one
that I had um bookmarked. Yeah, that
that I had bookmarked. Um, but
essentially there's another way to uh
pop XSS that just kind of recently uh
came out. Um, and that is using these uh
object or embed here. Let me go ahead.
I'll go ahead and share my screen as
well. But it's using object and embed
and it's using an attribute which I
haven't seen before um called code base.
And like I said, I haven't actually um
had the chance to deep dive this since
I'm recording this episode right after
coming back from vacation. Uh but they
provide just simply a hashtag in the
source or data attribute of these two
things. And this is trig triggering
JavaScript execution on Firefox. Um so I
I mean this is one of those things
that's really going to break a lot of
like W related stuff. Um because
typically, you know, they're looking for
onvent handlers and stuff like that. Um,
but this one actually allows you to
provide a JavaScript URI and uh it it
triggers. Um, so definitely a good I
don't know how long this is going to
last, but definitely one to keep in mind
now if you're dealing with a W um and
you want to get a pop in a in a Firefox
environment. So why does Gareth say this
second thing work? Like did you see his
tweet? I Yeah, with with like you're
talking about with data equals hashtag
and then the new line. Yeah, it's it's
both a new line. Here I'm sharing it.
It's both a new line, but it's also like
up here. Up here it makes sense, right?
It's JavaScript col alert. Here it's
JavaScript slash and then somehow fires
this alert. Super weird. So, I'm going
to I'll see if I can pull up the docs
for it right now as we're talking. Um,
well, while you're doing that, I I had a
question. Is there a way to look for
other words like codebase here? Like I
don't know. I guess that's like a key
and a key value pair. Are there other
object related keys that like have been
underexplored that we could look for? I
mean absolutely is the answer to that
question. But um essentially I'm pulling
up the the um Firefox docs for this
specific thing cuz like I said I I
haven't had the chance to um to to deep
dive it super much. So we're kind of
going to do this live here. And it looks
like codebase is actually deprecated. Um
but it it says the base path used to
resolve relative URI specified by class
ID, data or archive if not specified uh
the default is the base URI of the
current document. So essentially what
this is uh affecting the base URI uh
that is getting integrated into um
resolving these these um data and um
object uh tags. Uh and and so that's why
Gareth's thing here is is interesting
with the hashtag in the new line because
uh he provides uh a JavaScript UI in the
beginning. So JavaScript colon slash. So
when you do JavaScript slash that starts
a comment inside of the JavaScript, you
know, context, right? So JavaScript
colon now you're in JavaScript slash is
a comment and then he specifies a
hashtag as a part of this this URL that
would be a part of the fragment and then
a new line which is going to break out
of that comment in in JavaScript right
and then run alert one interesting um so
this is quirky as heck it's really
quirky it's cool really quirky and I and
I think that um this is another really
great example of base related
functionality uh being super interesting
for hackers because if you are able to
affect the domain or more importantly
really the protocol um that a given tag
is using by modifying it whatever its
base configuration is um then you can do
a lot of really stuff that's crazy it's
deprecated this has been around probably
used by some random thread actor for
years you know totally yeah and great
find by I I want to say it's Masa
Kinagawa that found it first um but I
know that uh that other people have sort
of built on that research Yeah, cool. I
think you had something for Jorian. Oh,
yeah. I can quickly say something
though. Um, yeah, go for it. We already
mentioned the drama, but one thing that
came out around the same time, and this
is actually back, I guess a nice
transition from the other hatex thing.
He, you know, said something along the
lines of like I don't know is the are
the plat hacker one or um bug bounty
platforms training AI models on user
data. So, I um obviously I don't work at
any of those companies, so I don't know
10,000% sure, but I've talked with a lot
of those leaders that we mentioned
earlier. And to my knowledge, there are
no companies, no bug companies that are
training models um or even fine-tuning
models on hacker submissions. So, just
want to clear that up. I I don't you
know, obviously one day it may happen or
something. I will say I've had
conversations with them about whether
hackers would be upset about that and
I've said yes every time. Um I I I do
think I do think there is some reality
where some hackers agree to give up
their reports for some sort of money in
exchange for letting those be trained
upon. And I think that makes perfect
sense because it's like our intellectual
property. I know in some ways you kind
of give it away depending on what you've
signed for what platform or program
whatever. a lot of major companies like
Fortune um 50 for Fortune 100 companies
a lot of times whenever you're signing
up for their bug bounty program you
actually are giving them the rights to
that intellectual property but um I do
think that that may happen in the future
I actually don't think it's that
valuable right now just because these
models get so much smarter and when you
do fine-tune them for a specific thing
they actually get worse you and I have
tested a cyber security model
specifically Google has released
multiple cyber security specific models
and they're just worse than the bigger
better models so I don't actually know
that there's a lot of value in these
companies even doing it yet. But I do
think that as cyber security becomes a
bigger AI safety threat, um it's
possible that they'll want them or as
these hackbot companies grow and have
the money to potentially purchase the
data set and they want to use those as
like rag where they pull in really good
examples of exploits. Yeah. Yeah. I
think I think using it for rag has a lot
more value than model fine-tuning. Yeah.
Um but uh yeah I mean I want to echo I
have talked to um at least Hacker One
and Bug Crowd um and I know that they
are not doing it. Um I do not know if
Sync is not doing it. I not to say that
they are. I just don't know. So I don't
want to be put on air of saying that all
the top platforms are not doing it. But
um yeah I know that at least Hacker One
and Bugout are not. Um
uh so yeah I think it's important to
note uh but yeah I think you hit the
nail on the head where I think rag is a
lot more important part of this uh so I
think converting all those into
embeddings will at some point be uh
necessary and I think it I think it's
really interesting that like what what
you said of maybe at some point these
companies say hey Justin you have you
know 2,000 submissions here we'd like to
rag this here's 250 grand and I'm like
yeah why why wouldn't you in my opinion
I mean it's basically getting more value
out of the um value you've already added
or it's like more value out of the work
you've already put in. Yeah. Yeah. I
mean it's going to cost them a [__] ton
of money to buy that data and who knows
maybe they'll they'll steal it from us
like you said you know but I think that
um right now that is not happening. So
yeah. Yeah. It it would be interesting
if there are any lawyers or smart people
out there to know uh what kind of um
what kind of rights or what kind of
things we could do to protect ourselves
in that regard if it were to ever
happen. Like I would love to know kind
of what the recourse is if it were to
occur because I think right now we're
kind of as a society trying to figure
out what that looks like in the form of
intellectual property of writing in that
goes into these models. And definitely
the art community is trying to figure
out what it looks like. I don't know if
you saw Disney just sued Yeah.
Midjourney for training on their stuff
or something. And so it's going to be
interesting to see how all this shakes
out. And I think it'd be nice to know
what our kind of um recourse going to
set precedent for hackers for sure.
Yeah. Um all right, last one that I had
was once again Jorian popping out some
crazy stuff. I I tell you just tweets
out and says, "Hey, I'm not sure you
guys know about the debug function in uh
Chrome's DevTools." And when I first
read that, I was like, "Yeah, I know
about the debug function." Like, of
course I know about the debug function,
but I did not know about the debug
function. Um, so listen up for a sec if
you if you do client side hacking. Um,
essentially what he is saying here is
that uh this this function debug uh in
Chrome, which is different, not to be
confused with the debugger directive in
Chrome. um actually allows you to kind
of do almost DOM logger++ like hooking
or like proxy like hooking where you can
specify a specific prototype function.
In this example, he specifies DOM
parser.prototype.parse from string.
Something that's used to obviously parse
uh HTML and convert it into a DOM. Um
and then triggers a breakpoint on that
specific function. Uh and that was not
something that I was familiar with and I
think is really helpful for that quick
and dirty. I hate I hate setting break
points. I still don't understand it to
be totally honest. And so I think this
is going to be something I could
potentially use to like get quick and
dirty break points without having to
like rightclick set it. Oh my. And
doesn't it sometimes go away? Like you
can lose break points so easily in the
Chrome Dev Tools. It it depends on the
way that the site is structuring their
JS files and it's a massive pain in the
butt when like um the name of JS files
is like changing every time you refresh
and you're like, "Oh, I can't set up." I
mean, sometimes though, like even if you
set it and it's not doing that, if you
accidentally click it to delete it,
right? Like if you click it, it's gone,
right? You can't recover it. Yeah. Yeah.
Sometimes. And and there's also quirks
of like, oh, I disabled this breakpoint,
but it's still triggering. And just dev
tools for being one of the like very
essential tools is a little bit buggy, I
have to say. Um uh so anyway, this is
another cool cool piece. And then one of
the people from um uh the comment
section uh says that there's a write up
uh by Bentowski which is an amazing uh
researcher at Google Zeroday project um
where he sort of covers this a little
bit more uh specifically talking about
how the debug directive back in the day
was shared by by the process not by the
the origin so that you could set a debug
directive on one on like you know blah
blah blah.google.com google.com and it
would allow you to get XSS on
ww.google.com, email@google.com, all
these other things if it was, you know,
inputed directly into the dev console.
Yeah. Um, which, you know, is not the
most impactful vulnerability, but is
something that is not what I would have
expected and would potentially have
caused even an advanced user, right, of
of DevTools and of uh, you know, Chrome
to have some unintended consequences.
Yeah. Uh, so definitely interesting
reads both on this and just knowing how
the debug function works. Before you
stop sharing, what is the dollar value
there on tweets? Is that are that are
you in like a beta group, a beta test
for showing how much money is from each
impression? I don't have that. This
right here. Yeah, I think maybe this is
a Chrome extension or something like
that that like, you know, calculates the
number of views by the average uh like
payout on Twitter or something like
that. So, I didn't know you had that.
It's it's interesting. you can just be
like, "Okay, you know, this tweet got
2,767 views and it's worth seven cents,
right?" You know, if you're a if you're
a uh uh monetized um Sure. person. So,
cool. Cool. Anyway, definitely cool. And
then I kind of went a little bit deeper
on this uh just I was cuz I was mad that
I didn't know about this and I was like,
where are the docs for this? And the
docs are like super hard to find uh for
this. And I did track down some of them,
which is just like a essentially a blog
post from developer.chrome.com.
chrome.com sort of explaining how it
works. Um, and you can see, you know,
that a function is being passed directly
into the debug function uh here. But
it's kind of hard to actually like pull
up the docs on how exactly this works.
But I have seen um other places where
it's used and there's like a condition
being passed in as like the second
parameter. But at least the first
parameter I is certain and that is a
reference to a specific function or
prototype where you want to cause a
breakpoint to occur. So definitely good
to know about. Yeah, very cool. I don't
have anything else. I, you know, I think
we pulled out uh two pretty neat things
to talk about on a future episode or
Yeah, maybe it's a bonus episode or
something, so we can do that. But yeah.
Yeah, let's do it. Let's call it a wrap
for today. Yeah. Cool. Thank you guys
for sticking with us. Peace. Bye. And
that's a wrap on this episode of
Critical Thinking. Thanks so much for
watching to the end, y'all. If you want
more critical thinking content, uh or if
you want to support the show, head over
to ctbb.show/isord. show/isord. You can
hop in the community. There's lots of
great highlevel hacking discussion
happening there on top of master
classes, hackalongs, exclusive content,
and a full-time hunters guild if you're
a full-time hunter. It's a great time.
Trust me. All right, I'll see you there.